# Jingyuan Zhang

3586 University Drive, Fairfax, VA 22030, USA jzhang33@gmu.edu | +1(571)278-4104

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

- My research interests include distributed systems and cloud computing. Specifically, serverless
  computing breaks the traditional server-based monolithic application models into fine-grained functions
  and allows tenants to pay-per-use. My current research focuses on providing in-memory object storage
  which is completely built and deployed atop ephemeral cloud functions. A typical application of my
  research is to accelerate data analytics workloads.
- I have spent three years as a cloud-based system architect and have over ten years of hands-on experience in system development.

### **EDUCATION**

# Ph.D. student in Computer Science

George Mason University

Aug. 2018 - Present Fairfax, VA, USA

# **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Technology**

Shanghai Jiaotong University

Sep. 1999 - June. 2003 Shanghai, China

### **PUBLICATION**

### InfiniCache: Exploiting Ephemeral Serverless Functions to Build a Cost-Effective Memory Cache

Ao Wang\* and Jingyuan Zhang\*, Xiaolong Ma, Ali Anwar, Lukas Rupprecht, Dimitrios Skourtis, Vasily Tarasov, Feng Yan, Yue Cheng

18th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST'20)

\*These authors contributed equally to the work.

## In Search of a Fast and Efficient Serverless DAG Engine

Benjamin Carver, Jingyuan Zhang, Ao Wang, and Yue Cheng 4th International Parallel Data Systems Workshop (PDSW'19)

## HyperFaaS: A Truly Elastic Serverless Computing Framework

Jingyuan Zhang, Ao Wang, Min Li, Yuan Chen, and Yue Cheng

In Posters of the 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI '19)

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# InfiniCache: Orchestrating Ephemeral Cloud Functions to Build A Cost-Effective Object Cache

2019

2020

2019

2019

Supervised by Prof. Yue Cheng, building from scratch, InfiniCache is a first-of-its-kind in-memory object caching system that is completely built and deployed atop ephemeral serverless functions. The paper is accepted by the 18th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST'20).

# HyperFaaS: A Truly Elastic Serverless Computing Framework

2018 - 2019

Serverless computing breaks the traditional server-based monolithic applications into fine-grained functions. However, the scalability and elasticity of serverless computing platforms are hampered due to huge container startup overhead. HyperFaaS, supervised by Prof. Yue Cheng, aims to maximize the resource utilization via hierarchical scheduling and intra-tenant container sharing.

### **Path Finding Algorithm with Traffic Rules**

2003

Undergraduate Project (Thesis). A\* algorithm is generally applied in path finding in GIS systems. Yet when traffic rules of real world are considered, we cannot apply the algorithm directly. So, a higher

abstraction of road network is devised in the paper, which allows algorithm to work again. My research report for this project was awarded rank A.

### AWARDS AND HONORS

FAST '20 Student Grant 2020

**USENIX** Association

NSDI '19 Student Grant 2019

**USENIX** Association

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# **Principal Systems Architect**

Oct. 2015 – Jun. 2018

Shanghai Bamaying Education Technology Co. Ltd.

Shanghai, China

• Ensure on-schedule launching of projects by defining server-side API interface and deployment specifications, including technology stack and monitor/backup policy.

Featured projects—

- Collaboration with Harvard University researchers on online psychological tests on parenting, with data analytics support.
- Online product categories focus on reviews. Several review promotion methods are applied, including displaying count of reviews and reducing the effort to review products.
- O Design, and oversee development of official iOS application of Bamaying;
- Initial deployment time of projects reduced by 90% by introducing and promoting docker-based deployment.

# **Systems Architect/Technical Director**

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2015

The World Traveller Co. Ltd.

Shanghai, China

• Supervised development of series of website/iOS applications to ensure timely delivery and high availability and scalability.

Featured projects:

- o ditu.uutuu.com: DIY map maker for travelers, featuring an elegant POI organizer, multiple map providers support, and data synchronization between mobile devices.
- o mico.cc: Location-based social network, featuring gamification of social network, and social API gateway.
- www.uutuu.com: Travel social community, featuring travel wiki, photo sharing, and full-page Javascript application for photo editing.
- o tripo: iOS social networking application for posting travel experiences, featuring intelligent queue management for photo sharing and large-scale image processing.

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Mar. 2005 – Mar. 2007

The9 Limited

Shanghai, China

- The principal programmer of interactive features of World of Warcraft website in China, including highcapacity bulletin board system.
- Main contributor of KPI indicators for game data analysis.
- Employed GUI to design XML-based task scheduling toolkits for automated data gathering and analysis.
- Developed real-time staticization engine that increased capacity to 100,000 simultaneous active users.

**Programmer** Jun. 2003 – Nov. 2004

NEC Solution China Co. Ltd.

Shanghai, China

• Delivered outstanding website products to Japanese clients, which were delivered on time with minimal bugs detected by client, including an online auction platform and an online banking system.

### INTERNSHIP

**Programmer** Jul. 2002 – Jun. 2003

Shanghai Changxiang Computer Co. Ltd.

Shanghai, China

Independently studied specification of GDF (a spatial data file format) and developed a map viewer for GDF later on. An algorithm used to solve path finding problem in GDF viewer is then suggested and accepted by internship supervisor.